

SOFTWARE DATA ENGINEER

□ (+98) 910-547-6014 | **□** rezaqavi1379@gmail.com | **□** RezaQavi-git | **□** rezaqavi

"I do something, You do something, now lets do something more, but together."

Summary.

Master's in Computer Engineering specializing in Software Engineering. Experienced in data engineering and a little hands-on in Python, NodeJS, Golang and any language if I have one week to learn it:) . A person who never shies away from challenges or change. Currently as a software engineer with a smile?.

Education

Shahid Beheshti University

Tehran, Iran

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING (SOFTWARE ENGINEERING)

2023 - Present

• GPA: 17.5/20

University of Tehran

Tehran, Iran

BACHELOR OF Science in COMPUTER Engineering (SOFTWARE Engineering)

2018 - 2023

• Last two academic years' overall GPA: 18.26/20 (Total GPA: 16.89/20)

Shahid Beheshti High School, under the supervision of NODET (National Organization for Developing Exceptional Talents)

Qaen, Iran

DIPLOMA IN MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

2014-2018

• GPA: 19.98/20

Work Experience_

TAPSI Tehran, Iran

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Dec 2023 - Present

 Overseeing the enhancement and upkeep of micro-services aimed at incentivizing and engaging drivers, ensuring optimal performance and user satisfaction.

- Optimizing system architecture for scalability, flexibility, and reliability.
- Involve in design and implementation of a SmartRebate project(write in Golang), witch include AI model for prediction, and use this service in TAPSI main flow for rebating drivers
- Involve in design and implement Driver Loyalty Club service, witch is responsible for provide infrastructure for scoring, and tiering users, and provide multiple rewards for each tier(on-going project)
- Actively contributing to problem-solving and solution implementation in various financial projects, ensuring financial stability and success.
- Refactored legacy code-base to improve maintainability and scalability, ensuring smooth operation and reducing technical debt.

TAPSI Tehran, Iran

DATA ENGINEER

June 2022 - Dec 2023

- Tapsi is an online cab e-hailing and ride-sharing platform. Having hundreds of thousands of rides per day, its infrastructure has huge performance, network, and availability challenges.
- Conducting a needs assessment and implementing strategic planning for the enhancement of JupyterHUB services. The goal is to optimize speed, scalability, and overall performance to deliver an improved experience for our data analysis and AI teams.
- Participate in the design and implementation of a new Change Data Capture (CDC) sync pipeline.
- · Add more visibility, add monitoring on Apache Kafka and Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS)
- Implementing an automated process for cleaning up files in both the local file system and Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS). The service will delete files that are no longer needed based on a specified retention time.
- Exploring and designing a comprehensive business-focused pipeline to automate various tasks.
- Upgrading the Apache Zeppelin, Apache Spark cluster, Apache Airflow
- Enhance data security by implementing Apache Ranger for resource-level data authorization.
- Develop a read/write utility for improved user experience with our data lake storage (HDFS), also ensuring compatibility with our object storage (Ceph cluster). This utility will enable seamless interaction across both storage systems.

University of Tehran Tehran, Iran

Bachelor Project Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

• Developing a stock market prediction platform that utilizes historical data from the crypto market, with a specific emphasis on extracting features and predict future market trends. (Python, Django)

Reza Qavi

University Selected Projects _____

	Moodle - Introduction to Computing Systems and Programming,	
Fall 2018	Implemented a system for managing and manipulating courses, students, and grades Developed using	С
	linked list, memory allocation, and structs in C	
Spring	Netflix - Advanced Programming,	C++, HTML,
2019	Developed an OOP application like Netflix with C++ Implemented a simple UI using HTML and CSS	CSS
	Operating System Projects,	
Fall 2020	Developed a client-server application using socket programming via UDP and TCP protocol Developed a multi-process application and used named and unnamed pipes for IPC	C++
	Developed a multi-thread program using the Pthread library for calculating an AI model accuracy	
	Artificial Intelligence Projects,	
Spring 2021	Implemented several conscious and unconscious search algorithms for solving the snake and seed problem Implemented a genetic algorithm for designing a logic circuit with a given truth table Implemented a Naive Bayes Classifier for classifying an online shop's comments Implemented several simple machine learning regressions using scikit-learn to predict house prices	Python
	Implemented a neural network for COVID-19 diagnosis using CT scan images of lungs.	
	Computer Network Projects,	
Spring 2021	Developed a simple FTP-server application using socket programming Implemented a simple version of Ethernet switch	C++
	Implemented a simple version of a router for sending multicast messages	
	Bolbolestan - Internet Engineering,	
Spring 2021	A unit selection system web application like "Golestan" with MVC architecture Back-end developed using Spring and MySQL Front-end	Spring,MYSQL, ReactJS,Docker
	developed using ReactJS Application deployed using Docker and Kubernetes	
Spring	Computer Networks Security,	Python
2022	Implemented both encryption and decryption modules for A5-1 stream cipher using Python	Fytholi

Skills_____

Programming, Python, Go, JavaScript, Bash, NodeJS, Kotlin (intermediate)

Technologies, K8s, Git, Linux, Docker, Spring, SQL, Rest API, Spark, Hadoop, Airflow

Soft Skills, Creative, Motivated, Communicative, Hard-working, Organized, Introvert

Others, Object-Oriented Programming, Software Development Methodologies, Agile, Multi-Thread Programming, Socket Programming, Big Data Proccessing, ETL

Reza Qavi

TAPSI